{
  "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
  "name": "Power Tools",
  "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "Guards on bench grinders should cover",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "1/4 of the wheel.",
        "1/3 of the wheel.",
        "1/2 of the wheel.",
        "2/3 of the wheel."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["2/3 of the wheel."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "The gap between the tool rest and the grindstone on a bench grinder should never be more than",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "1.6 mm (1/16'').",
        "3 mm (1/8'').",
        "6 mm (1/4'').",
        "12 mm (1/2'')."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["3 mm (1/8'')."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "A grinding wheel is classified by",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "The size and type of abrasive and the type of bonding agent.",
        "The size and width of the stone.",
        "The outside diameter and the size of the arbor hole.",
        "The shape and colour of the wheel."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["The size and type of abrasive and the type of bonding agent."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "A safety specification to consider when selecting a grinding stone or disc is",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "The grit size of the abrasive.",
        "The type of bonding material used.",
        "The rpm rating of the stone or disc.",
        "The size of the tool."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["The rpm rating of the stone or disc."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "A dressing tool is used for",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Putting a fine finish on ground edges.",
        "Refacing the surface of grindstones.",
        "Squaring the tool rest to the grindstone.",
        "Checking the clearance between the grindstone and the rest."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Refacing the surface of grindstones."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "Bouncing or heavy vibration of the workpiece when grinding are indications that the grindstone is",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "A coarse grit.",
        "Travelling too fast.",
        "Out of round.",
        "Worn out."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Out of round."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "Before installing a new grindstone, you need to",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Install a flat washer.",
        "Roll it across the floor to check for out-of-round conditions.",
        "Inspect the wheel for cracks.",
        "Lubricate the centre hole."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Inspect the wheel for cracks."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "The risk of the drill bit grabbing the work or breaking",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Increases as the bit is breaking through the workpiece.",
        "Can be avoided by using adequate lubricant.",
        "Can be minimized by running the drill faster.",
        "Only occurs when drilling hardened steels."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Increases as the bit is breaking through the workpiece."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "A V-block should be used when drilling holes in",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Round material.",
        "Angle iron.",
        "Non-ferrous material.",
        "Items where very accurate hole dimensions are needed."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Round material."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "Hand drills are rated by the",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Horsepower rating.",
        "Maximum rpm.",
        "Depth they can drill.",
        "Size of the chuck."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Size of the chuck."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "Tapered shanks are most common on",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Small drill bits.",
        "Large drill bits.",
        "Number drill bits.",
        "Letter drill bits."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Large drill bits."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "Slots in the drill press table are provided for",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Mounting the drill head.",
        "Draining the cutting fluid.",
        "Clamping jigs to the table.",
        "Securing the column."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Clamping jigs to the table."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "A magnetic base drill press is an advantage when:",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Drilling non-ferrous metals.",
        "Very accurate drilling is required.",
        "Holes are drilled in the vertical plane.",
        "The cutting chips need to be recovered."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Holes are drilled in the vertical plane."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "The main reason for using templates when forming steel is to",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Maintain accuracy.",
        "Increase production.",
        "Eliminate tactical errors.",
        "Impress your boss with your pattern development skills."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Maintain accuracy."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "One advantage of a vertical band saw is that it",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Permits better operator visibility.",
        "Can be used to cut curves.",
        "Provides easy access for blade changes.",
        "Shuts itself off when the cut is completed."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Can be used to cut curves."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "Safe cutting of angle iron in a cut-off saw requires",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "A labourer to do the work.",
        "One vertical leg of the angle iron against the stationary block of the clamping device.",
        "One vertical leg of the angle iron against the adjustable block of the clamping device.",
        "Both legs of the angle iron resting on the tool base."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["One vertical leg of the angle iron against the stationary block of the clamping device."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "Air tool governors would most likely be found on",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Grinders.",
        "Chipping hammers.",
        "Screwdrivers.",
        "Impact wrenches."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Grinders."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "Which of the following is the most important to consider in maintenance of a chipping hammer?",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "Blades.",
        "Piston.",
        "End plates.",
        "All of the above."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Piston."],
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "id": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "topicId": "0086c556-5b1b-4ca3-a1e2-91f1aed75b57",
      "question": "Most air tools are designed to operate at",
      "type": "single_type",
      "options": [
        "60 psi of air pressure.",
        "70 psi of air pressure.",
        "80 psi of air pressure.",
        "90 psi of air pressure."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["90 psi of air pressure."],
      "explanation": ""
    }
  ]
}
